《行尸走肉》
亲爱的
Hey, darlin'.
醒醒
Wake up.
亲爱的 醒醒
Hey, darlin'. Wake up.
怎么了 我们需要…
What is it? Do we need to …
不用 暂时没事
No, no, no. We're okay for now.
你也下午好
Well, good afternoon to you.
你来了
You're here.
是啊
Yeah.
现在见到你 我觉得浑身舒服
And I'm feelin' all kinds of glad to see you right now.
他们回来了吗
Are they back?
还没有
Not yet.
我知道你最近上夜班 今晚也是
I know you were pullin' late shift, and you wanna tonight,
所以我不想吵醒你
so I didn't want to wake you up.
玛姬有麻烦了
Maggie's in trouble.
什么
What?
孩子出了问题
Something with the baby.
瑞克要带她去找山顶寨的医生
Rick's taking her to the doctor at Hilltop.
他还不知道 但我要跟他去
He doesn't know it yet, but I'm going with him.
我只是
I just…
我知道我们才刚开始
I know we just started this,
- 但我希望你… - 别
- but I wanted you to… - Don't.
别什么
"Don't" what?
别走
Don't go.
欢迎来到你下半辈子的第一天 萨沙
Welcome to the first day of the rest of your life, Sasha.
你今天要帮我确保一切回归正轨
You are gonna help make sure things get back on track today.
你聪明性感
You are smart, hot as hell,
尊严高尚
dignified as shit,
你忍受不了蠢货
and you don't suffer one goddamn fool.
没人想看你死
No one's gonna wanna watch you die.
我就不想
I don't wanna see that.
所以你没必要死
So you don't have to.
但总得有人死
But someone does.
最多也许是几个人
Maybe a couple others … tops.
但你不用 大部分人也不用
But not you and not most people.
我们要解决一些问题
We are gonna help solve some shit.
尽情吃吧
Tuck in.
今天是个大日子
Big day.
你需要我做什么
What do you need from me?
看着我
Look at me.
为什么
Why?
因为我想阻止这一切
'Cause I want it stopped.
我想要尼根死
I want Negan dead.
那你为什么不杀他
So why don't you kill him?
我一个人做不到
Can't just be me.
他们都是尼根
They're all Negan.
你谋杀的那个女孩
That girl you murdered…
她有名字
She had a name.
她叫丹妮斯 是一名医生
Her name was Denise, and she was a doctor.
她救治了很多人
And she helped people.
我瞄准的不是她
I wasn't aiming for her.
动手 动手
Do it. Do it.
你想这样结束
You wanna end it this way…
随便你
You go ahead.
我很抱歉 真的
I'm sorry. I am.
我知道你很想
I know you want to.
他可能只是来看看你是否在的
He could just be here to see if you were here.
我们不能信任他
We can't trust him.
我曾是他的人
He owned me.
但不再是了
But not anymore.
我做的事
What I did,
都是为了某个人
I was doing it for someone else.
她最近跑掉了
She just got away.
所以我来了
So now I'm here.
那你是为了她吗
So are you because of her?
动手啊
Do it!
你还有另一个选择
There's another choice.
达里尔
Daryl.
- 达里尔 你认识她 - 尼根信任我
- Daryl, you knew her. - Negan trusts me.
我们可以合作 我们可以阻止他
We can work together, we can stop him.
你认识之前的我 也认识现在的我
You knew me then, and you know me now.
你知道我没有撒谎
You know I'm not lying.
我没有
I'm not.
动手啊
Do it.
动手
Do it!
他们抓住了萨沙 如果她还活着的话
They have Sasha, if she's even alive.
你为什么不早说
Why didn't you say something?
他可能是我们救回她的唯一机会
He could be our only chance to get her back.
因为我不信任他
Because I don't trust him.
但我信任达里尔
But I trust Daryl.
尼根马上就要来了
Negan's coming soon.
明天
Tomorrow.
大概会来三辆卡车
Three trucks probably.
他和二十名救世军
20 saviors and him.
我可以拖住他们
I can slow them down,
弄些树把路挡住
bring some trees down in the road,
为你们争取一点准备的时间
buy a little time for you guys to get ready.
假如你们能把他们干掉 我们就起了个好头
If you can take them out, that's where we start.
你们杀了他们之后 我就会发消息到救世堂
You kill them, I'll radio back to the sanctuary.
救世堂
The sanctuary?
尼根的住处
Where negan lives.
他们是这么叫的
That's what they call it.
我会发消息给他们 告诉他们一切顺利
I can radio back to them and say everything's okay.
你们把卡车开回去
You drive the trucks back,
我可以领着你们直捣黄龙
and I can lead you right inside,
假如计划得好 我们能把残党都干掉
and, with the right plan, we can wipe out the rest.
再去看看你们的朋友是否还活着
Check to see if your friend's still alive.
然后我们把工人拉拢到我们这边
Then, we get the workers on our side,
增加人数
build our numbers up,
然后一个个哨站杀过去 结束这一切
and go from outpost to outpost and end this.
继续说
Keep talking.
我们刚开始了 这整场战斗
We just started it … the whole thing.
假如他在撒谎 我会慢慢折磨死他
If he's lyin', I'm gonna kill him real slow.
等这一切结束了
When this is done,
我才不管他是不是悔过了
I don't give a damn if he's sorry.
我会杀了那个混蛋的
I will kill that son of a bitch.
假如他在撒谎
If he's lying,
我们早已经完了
this is already over.
我得走了
Oh, I gotta go.
事实上 我觉得我们可以…
Fact is, I figured we'd …
我做了一个梦
I had a dream.
你…
You…
你梦到我了吗
You had a dream about me?
你死了
You died.
计划就是这样
That's the plan.
这就是我需要你做的事
That's what I need from you.
你出来的时候 别吱声
And when you come out, not a peep.
他们会投降 假如他们还没有投降的话
They will stand down, if they haven't already.
然后 露西尔会杀掉三个人
And then, Lucille here, well, she gets her three,
然后我们带着全新的认知继续前行
and we move forward with a new understanding.
你是在…你是在逗我吗
Are you … are you shitting me?
那是真的眼泪吗
Is that real?
我可以配合 但没必要杀人
I can do it, but no one has to die.
你错了
You are wrong.
惩罚…
Punishment …
没它什么都做不成
Can't do anything without that.
我们拥有的一切都是建立在惩罚之上的
Punishment is how we built everything we have.
你以为我会坐视你…
You think I'm gonna sit here and let you…
当心点
Careful!
我做什么轮不到你说
You are not letting me do anything.
没必要死人
No one has to die.
好吧
Okay.
这样呢
How about this?
一个
One.
只死一个
Just one.
我本来打算选三个
I mean, I was gonna pull three outta the pool,
但只杀一个
but just one,
为你才这么做
and just for you.
好
Okay.
只用死一个人
Just one person has to die.
你真是把我玩弄于股掌之间
You got me wrapped around your little finger.
知道吗
You know that?
这跟男女无关
And it's not a man woman thing.
我是说 就算你有根老二
I mean, if you had a dick,
我还是会有这种感觉的
I would still have these feelings.
45分钟后出发
We roll out in 45.
我们没争取到海边旅馆 但我们有他们的枪
So we don't have Oceanside, but we have their guns.
而尼根手里有萨沙
Negan has Sasha.
达里尔希望我们相信德怀特
Daryl wants us to trust Dwight.
瑞克希望我们留在这以防不测
Rick wants us to stay here in case things go wrong.
这样还有另一手牌可打
so there's another card to play,
另一个救世军以为受他们控制的安全之处
another safe place the Saviors think they control.
但他不知道格雷戈里已经离开了
But he doesn't know that Gregory's gone…
也许他告诉了他们一些事
That maybe he's telling them things,
会让他们改变想法
that'll make them think something else.
这些都是会发生的
And it's all about to happen.
你在考虑领导山顶寨反抗
You're thinking of leading the Hilltop over there to fight.
是的
I am.
如果尼根发现他们在计划什么
If Negan finds out they're planning something,
他们就需要帮助了
they're gonna need help,
虽然那些拾荒者都站在他们那边
Even with those scavengers on their side.
你必须现在就决定
Well, you'd have to decide right now,
这可是个艰难的决定
and it's a very tough decision.
你笑什么
Why are you smiling?
因为我很高兴你是为我们做决定的人
'cause I'm glad you're the one making it for us.
该怎么决定
How do I?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道你能做出决定
I just know you can.
我来照顾她
Let me take her.
你拿着这个
You take this.
端起枪
Guns up, now.
怎么回事 他已经死了
What the hell? He's dead.
怎么了
What is it?
以前见过这个
We've seen this before.
跟以前一样
Same ones.
伙计 你没事吧
Dude, you okay?
- 你要一个人伏击他们吗 - 对
- You're gonna ambush them on your own? - Yeah.
现在不可以一个人单干
Going alone doesn't work for this.
我可以
It works for me.
你杀过他们的人了吗
Have you killed any of them?
因为如果你杀过 并且被他们发现了
Because if you have and they've found out,
他们也许会认为是神之国干的
they may think it was the Kingdom,
我们会失去有利条件
and we lose our advantage.
这是为了行尸搞的
It's from walkers.
我们能把路障移开吗
Can we move them aside?
你试图抹杀从前的自己吗
Do you seek to extinguish everything of who you were?
没有 但是
I don't seek it, but…
我不知所从
I'm stuck.
你想让救世军们死吗
You want the Saviors dead?
- 摩根 - 是的
- Morgan. - Yes, I do.
停止你的愚行
Cease this folly.
加入我的军队
Accompany my regiment.
救世军就像多头巨龙
The Saviors are a dragon with many heads,
兵多将广
their numbers legion.
我们必须寻求盟友与之一战
We must seek allies in this endeavor.
那是本杰明的盔甲
That's Benjamin's armor.
你穿着是为了保护自己 还是为了纪念他
Do you wear it to serve you, or do you wear it in his honor?
摩根
Morgan…
你没有走投无路
You are not stuck.
加入我们的旅程 结为盟友
Join us on this journey to create an alliance.
和我们一起战斗
Fight with us,
我们会打败他们 不会再让别人
and we shall defeat them so that no one will suffer.
被他们玩弄蹂躏
under their capricious malevolence ever again.
我们为了逝者
And we start once more for the fallen…
为了神之国
for the Kingdom…
为了胜利的荣耀再次战斗
…for the glory of victory.
你们为何而战
What you fight for.
不是为了这个地方 而是为了彼此
Not the place … the people, each other.
现在你们也是我们一员了
You're a part of that now.
我们只拿 不费心 这是我们的方式
We take. We don't bother …our way.
也许该换种方式了
Maybe another way.
你男人吗
Yours?
我们是在一起
Yeah, we're together.
我过后要睡他
I lay with him after.
你介意吗
You care?
- 该回去干活了 - 是啊
- We should get back to work. - Yeah.
你觉得是他们干的吗
Think this was them?
我想过
Crossed my mind.
我们有后备计划
We got a plan "B."
恕我直言
If I might be so bold…
这突然的阻碍让我
this unexpected stoppage has given me.
有机会能好好考虑一下
the chance for an exhaustive mull.
根据现在的严峻形势
Now, given the loaded circumstances.
还有潜在的伤亡和资源消耗
and potential for casualties and resource expenditure,
你能不能给我个机会
I was wondering if you would give me the opportunity.
去劝降他们 让他们冷静
to attempt to slow their jets and cool their roll.
你以前用过这种枪吗
You shoot one of these before?
很好
Good.
担心吗
Worry?
不
No.
很好
Good.
- 我去另一个塔 - 为什么
- I'll be on the next one over. - Why?
分头行动视野更好
It's more sight lines if we split up.
我去
I'll go.
你确定吗
You sure?
好吧
Okay.
我们会赢
We win.
是啊
Yeah.
你知道会发生什么事
You know what's gonna happen,
这会如何结束
How this is gonna end.
你知道会发生什么事
You know what's gonna happen,
这会如何结束
How this is gonna end.
我们要一起走出那扇门
We're gonna walk out that door together.
同甘共苦
We kick shit and eat snakes.
- 我们就是这样 - 我们这次可以袖手旁观
- That's us. - We can sit this one out.
反正他们也需要我们留在这
They need us here, anyway.
瑞克说要准备好战斗
Rick said to get ready for a fight.
我怎么死的
How'd I die?
我们当时在沙滩上
We were at the beach.
是在灾变前
It was before.
你被水卷了进去
You got pulled under…
没能出来
And you didn't come back up.
我试着去找你 但是你不见了
I was trying to find you, but you were gone.
然后 我开始溺水
And then, I started to drown.
我讨厌沙滩
I hate the beach.
穿着橡胶衣玩一天
End of the day in a wet suit?
回到车上的每一步
It's like you're sandblasting your nutsack.
蛋都像在被喷砂
every single step you take back to the car.
还好今天不去海边
Luckily, the seaside ain't on the agenda today.
就守卫和巡街
Just security and some road to chew.
好吗 来吧
All right? So, come on.
- 我们去帮玛姬 - 亚伯拉罕
- Let's go help Maggie. - Abraham.
什么
What?
这里需要我们
They can use us here.
就这一次 我们不逞英雄
Just once, we sit one out.
- 别人… - 应该是我们
- Someone else … - it should be us.
玛姬应该靠自己
Maggie's gotta take care of maggie.
吃过敏药的事
Have you, uh, changed your mind.
你有没有改变主意
about taking that allergy medication?
- 有 - 很好
- Yes. - Good.
我觉得你会适应这个地方的
I think you'll get adjusted to the place, sinus-wise.
不会的
No, I won't.
不像你
Not like you.
每个人都有自己的出路
Everyone has a way out.
别因为我的选择批判我
Don't go and yuck my yum for takin' mine,
顺便说 你也选的一样
which, I may add, is the same as yours now.
如果今天有人死 都是死在自己的选择上
If people die today, it's 'cause of the choices they made.
是啊 确实如此
Yeah. It is.
我们在这里做什么
Why are we here?
等这个
For this.
罗西塔
Rosita.
就位
Get into position.
我给你信号
I'll signal you.
墙没问题吧
And the wall's gonna hold?
没问题
It'll hold.
你们已被包围
All points are covered.
所有意外都在考虑内
Every contingency is already met.
我带着真相前来
I come armed with two barrels of the truth.
考验将至 而我给你们带来了小炒
A test is upon you, and I'm giving out the cheat sheet.
你们好
H-hello.
我前来劝降 因为我知道你们通情达理
I come salved with the hope that it is my dropped knowledge that you heed.
你们没有选择余地
Options are zero to none.
忠诚服从是唯一出路
Compliance and fealty are your only escape.
说白了 你们可生 亦或死
Bottom-lining it … you may thrive, or you may die.
我真心希望是前者
I sincerely wish for the former.
为所有人着想
For everyone's sake.
你们已经完全暴露了
The jig is up and in full effect.
投降吗 瑞克
Will you comply, rick?
尼根在哪
Where's Negan?
我是尼根
I'm Negan.
不
No.
我们会赢
We win.
你听过叫瑞克的小傻逼
You ever hear the one about the stupid little prick named rick.
以为自己本事大却一无所知
who thought he knew shit but didn't know shit.
害自己在乎的人被杀光的故事吗
and got everyone he that gave a shit about killed?
说的就是你
It's about you.
你们最好都把枪放下
You're all gonna wanna put your guns down now.
所有人别放下枪
No one drops anything.
我们说好的
We had a deal.
塔米尔去拿船上物资
Tamiel came for the boat things.
跟踪了夺走物资的人
Followed ones who took.
做了笔更好的交易
Made a better deal.
你一而再 再而三地逼我 瑞克
You push me, and you push me. And you push me, Rick.
你刚才想炸了我们是吧
You just tried to blow us up, right?
你想弄死我 我的人 我懂
I mean, I get me, my people.
但是尤金呢
But Eugene?
他可是你的人
He's one of yours.
他做了那事之后 他洗心革面了
And after what he did … he stepped up.
你们这些人
You people…
真是禽兽
are animals.
上帝给了你们启示
Universe gives you a sign, and you just.
你们却回了个中指 捅了他的菊花
shove your finger right up its ass.
德怀特 西蒙 快去
Dwight, Simon, chop-chop.
好吧 你们不喜欢尤金了
So, you don't like Eugene anymore.
但你们肯定喜欢萨沙
You guys gotta like Sasha.
我也喜欢
I do, too.
为了方便你们 我把她装在这里面了
Got her right here packaged for your convenience,
毫发无损
alive and well.
我带来了她 就不用杀了你们所有人了
Now, I brought her so I wouldn't have to kill all of you,
但不把你们都杀了 事情会变得很复杂
and not killing all of you could get complicated.
我知道里面还有很多武器 瑞克
See, I know there's a lot of firepower left in there, Rick.
我的要求很简单
So I'm gonna make this simple.
我要你们想方设法积攒来的所有枪
I want all the guns you've managed to scrape up.
是的 这个我也知道
Yep, I know about those, too.
我要你们剩下的所有柠檬粉
I want every last grain of lemonade you got left.
我还要你选一个人
I want a person of your own choosing…
送给露西尔
For Lucille.
达里尔
Daryl …
我得要回我的达里尔
Ooh, I gotta get me my Daryl back.
我看到你了
I see you.
还有台球桌
And the pool table.
全部台球杆和巧粉
and all the pool cues and chalk.
我现在就要
And I want it now.
不然萨沙就得死
or Sasha dies,
然后你们所有人都得死
And then all of you.
大概吧
Probably.
行了 瑞克
C'mon, Rick.
我把她装在棺材里带来
Just because I brought her in a casket.
不意味着她就得死在里面
doesn't mean she has to leave in it.
你知道吗
You know what?
你逊毙了 瑞克
You suck ass, Rick.
真的
You really do.
我不想杀她
I don't want to have to kill her,
但这正是你要逼我做的事情
but that's exactly what you're gonna make me do.
让我看看她
Let me see her.
好吧 给我点时间
All right. Just give me a second.
我也许得跟她说说现在什么情况了
I might have to get her up to speed.
在棺材里可什么都听不到
You can't hear shit inside this thing.
萨沙
Sash.
你绝对不会相信这破事的
You're not gonna believe this crap.
感觉很真实
It felt real.
像是失去了这一切
Like we lost this.
而我们才刚刚开始
And this just started.
- 走吧 - 等等
- C'mon. - Wait.
我喜欢你看穿我的样子
I like the way you call bullshit.
所以这次让我来帮帮你吧
So let me return the favor.
接下来你要跟我说的是
The next thing you're gonna tell me.
你会去 这样我就可以留下
is that you'll go and that I can stay.
因为我知道 你自己也不想说出
Because I know you didn't like hearing yourself just say.
「玛姬应该靠自己」这种话
that, "Maggie's gotta take care of Maggie."
我知道这句话会回荡在你脑中
I know those words are gonna choke in your ears.
很久很久
a good, long while.
你会因为仅仅有这念头而做出补偿
and you're gonna wanna make up for even thinking that.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
对
Yeah.
我们为别人置生死于度外
We lay our big meaties across the chopping block ahead of someone else's.
总是为别人
It's always for someone else.
我们都知道 如果我们要死
Both of us know, if we're gonna kick,
那最好死得有意义
there sure as hell better be a point to it.
所以或许我们觉得这一切都是有意义的
So maybe we feel there was a-a point to all of this.
自始至终
Alpha to omega.
不管是在战场 还是在海边
Whether it's on the battlefield or the beach.
还是别的什么地方
or somewhere out there today.
玛姬
Maggie …
她怀着未来
She's carrying the future.
你说得对
You're right.
我知道这会如何结束
I knew how this was gonna end.
走吧
C'mon.
为别人冒生命危险
Layin' your ass on the line for someone else,
为他们扫除障碍
Tearin' it to shreds for 'em …
你以前说过
You said it before.
这才叫活着
Oh, my, that is living.
你真是个傻瓜
You're an idiot.
我从没说过我不是
I never said otherwise.
去那里要几个小时 对吗
A couple hours to get there, right?
至少吧
At least.
路上也许障碍重重
Might be a circuitous and janky route.
鉴于他们在谋反 道路很可能被监视了
With what they're planning, they could be watching the roads.
「他们在谋反」
"What they're planning."
没错
That's right.
我在市集拿的 存满了歌
Got it in the marketplace. It's chock-full.
在旅途中恐怕无法交谈
Doubt conversation will be on tap for the commute.
尽管我是个自私的懦夫
And though I am a selfish coward,
我有时也会为别人着想
I do tend to think of other people on occasion.
请收下我的馈赠吧
Please take it with my compliments.
我真的希望我能做好人
I truly wish I measured up.
你依然可以 尤金
You still can, Eugene.
我不会放弃
I'm not giving up.
不会放弃你
Not on you.
天啊 你不用躺在那玩意儿里面过去
Jesus, you don't have to take the trip in the thing.
我想休息一下
I could use the rest.
不是吧
No shit?
是的
Yeah.
我只想睡觉
I just want to go to sleep.
给我一小杯水就行了
I just need a little bottle of water, and I'm fine.
阿拉特
Arat?
听着
Listen…
我知道这有多难
I know how tough this is.
我很感激
And I appreciate it.
该死 你真了不得
Damn, you are something else.
（正在播放 《总有一天 我们都会自由》 唐尼·海瑟威）
萨沙
Sash.
你绝对不会相信这破事的
You're not gonna believe this crap.
我的妈呀
Holy goddamn!
快走
Go! Go!
别
No.
亲爱的 该死
Aah! honey, god damn it!
那就后备计划吧
Plan "B" It is!
跪下 快点
Down. Now.
我们可以重新做笔交易
We can make another deal.
我说了跪下
I said, down.
又见面了
Hello again.
跪下 不然再吃一枪
Down. Or again.
靠 瑞克
Well, shit, Rick.
你就不能老实跟着我们吗
You just couldn't stick with us, huh?
非要找这些捡破烂的脏人
You had to go with these filthy garbage people?
无意冒犯
No offense.
说好了是12个 对吗
Deal is for 12, yes?
10个
10.
人才是资源
People are a resource.
12个
12.
10个挺好
10.
瑞克
Rick.
这会让你难过的
This is just gonna make you sad.
心碎
Broken.
你会希望你死了
You're gonna wish you were dead.
我喜欢闹着玩
I like having fun.
真的
I do.
但也许你觉得对你朋友做出那种事的人不是我了
But maybe you think that the guy that did what he did to your friends wasn't me,
以为那不过是某种作秀
like that was some sort of a put-on,
以为我不是拿着大棒的人
like I'm not the guy with the bat …
只是个给你孩子做意面的人
I'm just the guy that makes your kid spaghetti.
草
Oh, shit.
也许这怪我
Maybe this is on me.
也许这全都怪我
Maybe this is all on me.
我必须纠正错误
I gotta make it right.
我猜又要重来一遍了
I guess I gotta start all over again.
必须告诉你 瑞克
I gotta tell you, Rick,
假如我有孩子
if I had a kid,
我希望他跟你孩子一样
I'd want him to be just like your kid,
所以这就更难了
which makes this so much harder.
你赢不了的
You're not gonna win.
卡尔
Carl.
已经结束了
It is over.
何不用你的独眼
Why don't you point your one ball.
看看那边 感受一下
up the street there and take it all in?
我们会赢
We'll win!
我们会活
We live!
是我们
We're the ones!
我们
Us!
你刚失去了某个重要的人 就在刚刚
You just lost somebody important to you right now … like, just now.
老天啊
Jesus.
时机真好
That is timing.
瑞克
Well, Rick…
这是你选的
you chose this.
我真不知道我还能怎么警告你
I truly don't know what more I could've done to warn you.
而且这不是警告了
And this isn't a warning.
这是惩罚
This is punishment.
我现在要杀了卡尔
I'm gonna kill Carl now.
我会狠狠地 重重地挥一棒
I'm gonna make it one nice, hard swing,
试着一击毙命 因为我喜欢他
try to do it in one because I like him.
我只想让你把这个念头放进脑子里
I just want you to put that in your brain.
细细回味一下
and roll it around for a minute.
我会杀了卡尔 然后露西尔
I'm gonna kill Carl, and then Lucille here,
她会砸烂你的双手
she's gonna take your hands.
你可以就在我面前做
You can do it right in front of me.
你可以砸烂我的双手
You can take my hands.
我已经告诉过你了
I told you already …
我会杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
你们所有人
All of you.
也许不在今天 也许不在明天
Maybe not today, maybe not tomorrow…
但没有什么能改变这点
but nothing is gonna change that …
没有什么
Nothing.
你们已经死了
You're all already dead.
靠
Damn.
瑞克
Wow, Rick.
好吧
Okay.
你说了我可以做
You said I could do it.
灭了救世军和他们的同伙
End these Saviors and their accomplices!
亚历山大不会陷落 不在今天
Alexandria will not fall, not on this day!
方阵队形 第三队 上
Phalanx out, third group, now!
快上 我们掩护你们
Move up! Now we got your backs!
他妈的一头老虎啊
A goddamn tiger!
那寡妇没死 活蹦乱跳的
That widow is alive, guns a-blazin'!
你尝到了吗 西蒙 这就是吃屎的滋味
You taste that, Simon? That is the taste of shit!
他们撤退了
They're falling back.
爱德华多 伯蒂 去房屋之间
Eduardo, Bertie, between the houses …
掩护大门
Cover the gate!
走
Let's go.
现在收尾
Now we finish this!
上
Now!
拉
Pull!?
米琼恩
Michonne.
Michonne.?
你还活着
Oh, you're alive.
我们…
We … W-We're…
We're…
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.?
我知道
I know.
我们活下来了
We are.
我们会活下去
We will.
准备已就绪
Getting preparations in place.
所有人都是蓝色警戒
Everyone's on "Blue level."
只要你下令 他们就出发
You say the word, they're ready to go.
很好
That's good.
你觉得她怎么会死在棺材里
How the hell do you think she wound up dead in that box?
最可能的原因是油布
My, um, best possible posit fingers the tarp.
棺材被封得严严实实
That sealed up said box good and tight.
她用完了空气
She ran out of air.
也许吧
Maybe.
那么
So…
我们要开战了
we are going to war!
遵命
Yes, sir!
你觉得萨沙是一个人做到的吗
Do you think Sasha did that herself?
我不知道怎么做到的 但我知道她做到了
I don't know how, but I know she did.
她给了我们机会 你给了我们机会
She gave us a chance. You did.
你选择过来是正确的
You made the right decision to come.
这选择很早以前就做了
The decision was made a long time ago,
在我们大家相识之前
before any of us knew each other,
当我们还是在街上擦肩而过的陌生人时
when we were all strangers who would have just passed each other on the street.
在世界结束之前
before the world ended.
现在我们对彼此意味着一切
And now we mean everything to each other.
你遇到了麻烦 你陷入了困境
You were in trouble. You were trapped.
格伦不认识你 但他救了你
Glenn didn't know you, but he helped you.
他为你冒了生命危险
He put himself in danger for you.
这是一切的源头
And that started it all …
从亚特兰大 到我爸爸的农场
From Atlanta, to my daddy's farm,
到监狱
to the prison,
到这里
to here…
到此时此刻
to this moment now…
我们不再是陌生人
not as strangers …
而是家人
as family…
（当时不知道）
因为格伦那天选择救了你
because Glenn chose to be there for you that day.
很久很久以前
a long time ago.
而那个选择改变了一切
That was the decision that changed everything.
这是你们俩发起的
It started with both of you,
然后不断壮大
and it just grew…
如今我们所有人
to all of us…
为彼此做出牺牲
to sacrifice for each other…
承受苦难
to suffer and stand,
去哀悼 去给予
to grieve, to give,
去爱 去生活
to love, to live…
去为彼此而战
to fight for each other.
格伦做出了那个选择 瑞克
Glenn made the decision, Rick.
我不过是在追随他的脚步
I was just following his lead.